



About

Hi! My name is Inês (Portuguese pronunciation: i'neʃ). I'm 28 years old and live in London, UK. I moved here in early 2019 for work.

I have a bachelor in Informatics Engineering by the University of Coimbra and have been working as a software developer for a few years now.

My hobbies include reading and playing Minecraft. I also enjoy listening to the occasional podcast (Soft Skills Engineering and No Such Thing As A Fish being my favorites at the moment). At the end of 2020 I decided to add learning French and React to the list - my website is a result of the latter.

I'm always looking for interesting opportunities, so feel free to say hi!

igorplus ines.csim@gmail.com

J +44 7761 824051 (UK) / +351 935 889 881 (PT)

Education

Bachelor's Degree, Informatics Engineering at the University of Coimbra

O Sep 2012 to Aug 2017

• Coimbra, Portugal

Experience

Product Lead for Ethics Monitor at Haplo

O May 2019 to January 2021

• London, United Kingdom

Product lead for Ethics Monitor, which helps universities streamline the review of applications for ethical approval.

During my time at Haplo I worked closely with new clients throughout the process of building their custom application, provided support for existing clients and worked alongside my colleagues to improve the product.

Fossil

JavaScript

Software Developer at HYP

O Sep 2018 to Jan 2019

• Coimbra, Portugal

At HYP, I worked with a small team of developers and designers to develop BabyLoop, a platform to buy and sell used baby products (such as cribs, car seats, etc).

P GitLab

Ruby on Rails, Ruby, JavaScript

Junior Ruby Developer at OneSource

O Mar 2017 to Aug 2018

• Coimbra, Portugal

At OneSource, I was tasked with developing an extension for **SketchUp** to optimize the structure of any building designed by the user using the program. This was done using SketchUp's Ruby API and in collaboration with a team of civil engineers from the **University of Coimbra**.

As the only developer on the team, I was responsible for meetings with the client as well as reviewing and merging the code created by the civil engineers' team, making sure it worked seamlessly with the general extension code.

P GitHub

Ruby, JavaScript

Ruby on Rails Internship at HYP

O Jul 2016 to Sep 2016

• Coimbra, Portugal

Web application to pick movies to watch with friends, based on which movies everyone on the group wants to watch.



Ruby on Rails, Ruby, JavaScript

Skills

Programming

Git	★★★★☆		
React	★★★☆☆	Python	★★★☆☆
Ruby on Rails	$\bigstar \bigstar \bigstar \bigstar \diamondsuit$	Java	$\bigstar \bigstar \bigstar \diamondsuit \diamondsuit \diamondsuit$
Ruby	$\uparrow \uparrow \uparrow \uparrow \uparrow \uparrow$	HTML/CSS	$\bigstar \bigstar \bigstar \circlearrowleft \circlearrowleft$
Javascript	★★★★☆	Redux	★★★☆☆

Operating Systems

Linux	★★★☆ ☆	Windows	★★★★☆
MacOS	★★★★☆		

Languages

Portuguese	****	French	★★☆☆☆
English	****		